Guide to the Rubinsky Family Papers, 1991-2001 MS 866
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rubinsky Family Papers
1991-2001
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rubinsky, Karen
MS 866
.25 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection is made up of one box containing rosters/address books, calendars, camp information materials, publications, and religious school materials from the Rubinsky Family, spanning from 1991-2001.
Biographical / Historical
Karen Rubinsky grew up in Galveston, Texas. She earned two bachelor's degrees with high honors from the University of Texas at Austin: one in mathematics and one in computer science. She earned her master's degree in business administration with a concentration in management information systems from the University of Houston.
Karen is Assistant Vice President for Development and Alumni Operations at Rice University. Prior to going to Rice in 1993, Karen worked for 12 years at First City Bancorporation of Texas. Karen began her career as a programmer/analyst at Brown & Root, Inc. in Houston.
In addition to her work at Rice, Karen is active on committees of several nonprofit organizations in the Houston community.
Excerpt from: https://dar.rice.edu/karen-rubinsky
Scope and Contents
Address books, calendars, camp information materials, publications, and religious school materials document the lives of members of the Rubinsky family and their involvement in the Houston Jewish Community from 1991-2001. The papers especially demonstrate the family's involvement with Camp Young Judaea Texas and the Houston Jewish Community Center.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Series I: Address Books/Rosters has been restricted as they contain individuals' addresses and phone numbers. Permission to view these items must be obtained from the director of the Houston Jewish History Archive or the director of the Woodson Research Center.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in five series as follows: Series I: Address Books/Rosters; Series II: Calendars; Series III: Camp Information Materials; Series IV: Publications; Series V: Religious School Materials
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Karen Rubinsky donated the papers in April of 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life; Education
Document Types
directories; calendars; Informational works
- Series I: Address Books/Rosters, 1996-2001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials restricted as they contain individuals' addresses and phone numbers.
  - Texas, Oklahoma, Louisiana Young Judaea Convention Roster, 1996-01-19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Roster restricted as it contains individuals' addresses and phone numbers.
  - CYJ Camp Session Address Books, 1998; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CYJ 50 Years Roster 1952-2002, 2001-10-14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Calendars, 1997-2003
  - Camp Young Judaea Calendars, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CYJ Session One Calendar, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Camp Information Materials, 1991-1999
  - CYJ Early Bird Application, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - JCC Day Camp Information Packet, 1995-01 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CYJ Segel Summer Information, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - JCC Summer Camps Booklet, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CYJ Camper and Parent Manuals, 1996; 1999; 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CYJ Counselor in Training Summer Information Packet, 1999-05-06 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Publications, 1991-1999
  - CYJ Promotional Brochures, N.D.; 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Young Judaean Magazine Vol. 83 Issue II, Spring 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - JCC Houston Sports Camping Newsletter, 1995-07-28 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kol Hat'nua Young Judaea Newspaper Vol. 55 Issue 3, March/April 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Texas, Oklahoma, Louisiana Outlook Newsletters, April 1997; Spring 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series V: Religious School Materials, 1993-2001
  - United Orthodox Synagogues Talmud Torah Hebrew School Documents, 1993-08 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brith Shalom Religious School Handbook, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)